

Francesca Folkmer

UX/UI DESIGNER

I'm a UX/UI Designer based in Milan. I have always been in love with the world of art and design. I graduated in Set Design, and after three years of working in this industry, I decided to get back into the game. I joined start2impact and enrolled on the path of UI/UX Design.

EDUCATION

2022 - In progress

Start2impact University UX/UI Design Master

2015 - 2019

NABA - Nuova Accademia delle Belle Arti

Set Design

Graduated with full marks 110/110

2010 - 2015

Leonardo Da Vinci

Liceo Scientifico

CERTIFICATIONS

2022

Fastweb Digital Academy

UX/UI Design; Design System; UX and Psychology; UX Gamification; User Research

2020

Google Digital Training

Fundamentals of digital marketing

LANGUAGE

Italian Mother Language

English B2 Level

VOLUNTEER

2015 - 2020

Handicap Su La Testa

Disability Support

WORK EXPERIENCE

DEC 2022 - FEB 2023

UX/UI Designer Ennepi

Brand identity and website

SET 2018 - DEC 2021

Art Director and Set Designer Colibril2

Advertising sets, short films and social content

OTT 2020 - FEB 2021

Art Director Hovo Faber

Projects Presentation and social content

SET 2018 - DEC 2021

Set Designer Freelancer

Advertising sets, short films, and music videos.

EXTRA

During my studies I always worked as a waitress and bartender in order to support myself.

SKILLS

Hard Skills

Graphic Design

User Research

Usabilità, Accessibilità, User

Flow, User Stories

Wireframing and

Prototyping

Interfacce app, mobile, web

innovative e ad elevato

dettaglio

User Testing

HTML, CSS, Javascript

Design System

User Centered Design

Agile UX

Programs

Figma

Adobe XD

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Lightroom

Adobe Premiere

Keynote

Suite Office 365

AutoCAD

3Ds Max

ZBrush